Guide to the Stephen Farnum Peckham Papers, 1865-1881
Department of Special Collections
Stephen Farnum Peckham Papers,
1865-1881
Special Collections M387
Peckham, Stephen Farnum
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Diaries and letters gift of Mary W. Peckham, ca. 1920 and 1932; field notebook transferred from the Department of Geology, Stanford University, 1939.
BIOGRAPHY
Stephen Farnum Peckham, a chemist, was interested in the oil refining process, and particularly the occurrence of petroleum in Southern California.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
These papers consist of a journal (1865-1866) kept by Peckham (with some entries by his wife, Mary Chace Peckham, active in the suffrage movement) during their stay in San Buenaventura, California; correspondence between Peckham and geologists then working in California on the state survey; and Peckham's field notebook (ca. 1881) pertaining to eastern oil fields and refineries. Correspondents include William Henry Brewer, William More Gabb, Benjamin Silliman, George M. Wheeler, and Josiah Dwight Whitney. During the time period represented in his journal, Peckham worked for the California Petroleum Company.
The journal and most of the correspondence is interfiled chronologically, as Peckham, himself, kept his papers. The Whitney letters may in part have been kept in the journal but came to the library separately.
CONTAINER LIST
- Diary with inserted letters, clips, pictures, etc., 1865,pp 1-31. Inserted: (Folder 1)
  - 1865, Apr.Nathaniel Peter Hill to unknown. ALS
  - 1865, Jun 15.P.W. [Irving?] for Calif. Petroleum Company. Contract with Peckham.
  - 1865, Jun 13.Edward Books Hall. Marriage certificate of Peckham & Mary Chace Peck.
  - 1865, Jun 14.P.W. [Irving?] to Wm. H. Stone. Employment of Peckham.
  - 1865, Sept 30.C.T. Coggeshall to S.F. Peckham.
  - [1866?], Sept 28.James B. [no last name]
  - Photo of drawing (1870) of Ranch House No. 1.
  - Rancho Ojai - printed list of transfers, 1853-1870.
  - 2 diagrams of Ranch House.
  - Photograph, 1894.Asphalt cones and Sulfur Mountains, Upper Ojai.
- Diary, 1865continued, pp 32-61. Some entries bv Mary Peckham. Inserted: (Folder 2)
  - 1865, Oct 4SFP to W.H. Stone. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Oct 5SFP to Marcus A. Finch. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Oct 9SFP to John E. Williams. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Oct 23SFP to E. J. [Blanding]. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Oct 24Richard B. Duane to Mary C. Peckham. ALS
  - 1865, Oct 24SFP to M. A. Finch. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Oct 28SFP to C.T. Coggeshall. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Nov 15SFP to Edward J. Blanding. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Dec13SFP to John E. Williams. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1865, Nov 18E.B. Hall to Mr. and Mrs. Peckham. ALS
  - [1865?], Nov 19Louisa J. Hall to Mr. and Mrs. Peckham. ALS
  - Photograph, 1894.Last adobe home in San Buena Ventura.
  - 1865, Dec.Owen Mason to [SFP] ALS
  - Sketch map of Ojai-San Buena Ventura.
- Diary, 1866,pp 62-64. Inserted: (Folder 3)
  - 1866, Jan 1SFP to C.F. Coggeshall. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Jan 4SFP to Amasa M. Eaton. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Jan 13SFP to Maj. C. B. Raymond. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Jan 15SFP to Prof. Geo. I. Chase. ALS (letterpress,)
  - 1866, Mar 26SFP to Thos. R. Bard. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Mar 29SFP to M. A. Stone. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Apr 20SFP to L.H. Newton. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Apr 28SFP to G.A. Wheeler. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Apr 28SFP to J.D. Whitney. ALS(letterpress)
  - 1866, May 12SFP to Wm. H. Stone. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, May 15SFP to J.D. Whitney. ALS(letterpress)
  - 1866, Jun 7SFP to J.D. Whitney. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Apr 28Louisa J. Hall to Mrs. Peckham. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, May 15Louisa J. to Mrs. Peckham (letterpress)
  - n.d. Resolution, P.W. [Irving?]
  - 1866, Feb 10SFP report to California Petroleum Company, AMsS with diagrams, 22 pp
  - 1866, Feb 13SFP to John E. Williams. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Apr 24SFP to California Petroleum Company Holograph report, 18 pp
- Diary, 1866,pp. 65-94. Inserted: (Folder 4)
  - 1866, Jun 13SFP "Inhabitants of Lower California," typed article.
  - 1866, Jul 18SFP Typed article.
  - 1866, Oct 18Thomas A. [Scott] to SFP. ALS
  - 1866, Oct 8J.E. Williams to SFP. ALS
  - 1866, Nov 6Thomas R. Bard to SFP. ALS
  - 1866, Dec 19Thomas R. Bard to SFP. ALS
  - 1866, Jul 20Thomas R. Bard to SFP. ALS
  - 1866, Jul 23SFP to T.R. Bard. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Jul 19SFP to State Geological Survey of California (J.D. Whitney) receipted bill for expenses. (letterpress)
  - 1866, Jul 16SFP to Wm. M. Gabb. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Oct 16SFP to Thos. [J] Magill. ALS(letterpress)
  - 1866, Oct 17SFP to J.D. Whitney. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Oct 19SFP to Wm. H. [Brewer]. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Oct 31SFP to Geo. F. Barker. ALS(letterpress)
  - 1866, Nov [23]SFP to Thos. A. Scott. ALS (letterpress)
  - [1866], Dec 19SFP to J. D. Whitney. ALS (letterpress)
  - [1866], Dec 22SFP to Thos. R. Bard. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1866, Dec 26SFP to [Jona Letterman?]. ALS(letterpress)
  - 1867, Feb 4SFP to Benjamin Silliman, Jr., ALS(letterpress)
  - 1867, Feb 5SFP to J. D. Bark-[Llorbe?]. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1867, Feb 5SFP to John E. Williams. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1867, Feb 5SFP to [Thos. R.] Bard. ALS (letterpress)
  - 1867, Feb 9SFP to J.D. Whitney. ALS (letterpress)
- WHITNEY, JOSIAH DWIGHT [1819 -1896] (Folder 5)
  - 1866, Jan 8JDW to [SFP], ALS with note by Peckham.
  - 1867, Jan 18JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1867, Jun 9JDW to [SFP]. ALS
  - [1871], Jun 19JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1871, Dec 14JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1872, Jan 31JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1872, Apr 20JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1872, Jul 14JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1872, Oct 12JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1872, Oct 21JDW to [SFP]. ALS
  - 1873, May 17JDW to SFP. ALS
  - 1877, Sept 17JDW to SFP. ALS
- Field notebook of SFP, ca. 1881,re eastern oil fields, refineries, etc. (Folder 6)